<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-15T08:36:47+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Architectural AI Reseach Lab</title><subtitle>The AAIRL is revolutionizing Architecture and Urban Design by leveraging the power of computation, artificial intelligence, and collective intelligence, we are creating new design methods that will lead to more sustainable and equitable cities for a better future.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Conceptual Architectural Design at Scale - A Case Study of Community Participation Using Crowdsourcing</title><link href="/featured/2023/02/07/conceptual-design-at-scale.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conceptual Architectural Design at Scale - A Case Study of Community Participation Using Crowdsourcing" /><published>2023-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-15T08:34:07+00:00</updated><id>/featured/2023/02/07/conceptual-design-at-scale</id><content type="html" xml:base="/featured/2023/02/07/conceptual-design-at-scale.html"><![CDATA[<p>We published a new open access research paper.</p>

<p>Architectural design decisions are primarily made through an interaction between an architect and a client during the conceptual design phase. However, in larger-scale public architecture projects, the client is frequently represented by a community that embraces numerous stakeholders. The scale, social diversity, and political layers of such collective clients make their interaction with architects challenging. A solution to address this challenge is using new information technologies that automate design interactions on an urban scale through crowdsourcing and artificial intelligence technologies. However, since such technologies have not yet been applied and tested in field conditions, it remains unknown how communities interact with such systems and whether useful concept designs can be produced in this way. To fill this gap in the literature, this paper reports the results of a case study architecture project where a novel crowdsourcing system was used to automate interactions with a community. The results of both quantitative and qualitative analyses revealed the effectiveness of our approach, which resulted in high-level stakeholder satisfaction and yielded conceptual designs that better reflect stakeholders’ preferences. Along with identifying opportunities for using advanced technologies to automate design interactions in the concept design phase, we also highlight the challenges of such technologies, thus warranting future research.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.mdpi.com/2075-5309/13/1/222">Read the full paper</a></p>]]></content><author><name>ela-moyal</name></author><category term="featured" /><category term="participatory design" /><category term="AI" /><category term="chatbot" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We published a new open access research paper.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/papers/system.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="/images/papers/system.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">We invite you to a lecture “Mixing Worlds- Mixing Realities” By Dr.-ing. Gerhard Schubert</title><link href="/featured/2023/01/10/schubert-lecture.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We invite you to a lecture “Mixing Worlds- Mixing Realities” By Dr.-ing. Gerhard Schubert" /><published>2023-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-15T08:34:07+00:00</updated><id>/featured/2023/01/10/schubert-lecture</id><content type="html" xml:base="/featured/2023/01/10/schubert-lecture.html"><![CDATA[<p>Imagine a future where architects can design the way they are used
to today but get additional expert support from computational
systems. Can an integrated digital design assistant support
architects while modeling and sketching - assisting them
seamlessly like an expert looking over their shoulder?</p>

<p>This future is the future vision of the CDP // Collaborative Design
Platform research group at the Chair of Architectural Informatics
in the TU Munich School of Engineering and Design focuses on
the direct, seamless integration of digital tools into the creative
design process.</p>

<p>Founded in 2010, our team conducts research in the direct
field of tension between intuitive human-machine interfaces,
gamification methods, and artificial intelligence in urban planning
and architectural design. The core of our research is an interactive
architectural and urban design platform that serves as a seamless
interface between established physical tools and interactive
digital tools. In this way, the CDP // Collaborative Design Platform
supports decision-makers with the calculation and presentation
of objective criteria at a very early stage.</p>

<p>This lecture will present an overview of the CDP research
work and the state-of-the-art tools developed for future
architecture practice.</p>

<p>Dr. -ing. Gerhard Schubert is the Director of Research at the
Department of Architecture and Senior Researcher at the Chair for
Architectural Informatics at Technische Universität München. He
studied architecture at TU München with a focus on urban planning,
graduated as valedictorian in 2006, and finished his doctoral thesis
in 2014 with the highest distinction. Since September 2015, he
has held the position of director of research at the architecture
department.</p>

<p>Thursday, January 19, 2023</p>

<p>Lecture: 14:00 - 15:00</p>

<p>Raab Auditorium, Building 52</p>]]></content><author><name>ela-moyal</name></author><category term="featured" /><category term="participatory design" /><category term="AI" /><category term="augmented reality" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imagine a future where architects can design the way they are used to today but get additional expert support from computational systems. Can an integrated digital design assistant support architects while modeling and sketching - assisting them seamlessly like an expert looking over their shoulder?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/schubert.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="/images/schubert.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Toward a Generative Pipeline for an AR Tour of Contested Heritage Sites</title><link href="/featured/2022/12/20/towards-generative-vr.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Toward a Generative Pipeline for an AR Tour of Contested Heritage Sites" /><published>2022-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-15T08:34:07+00:00</updated><id>/featured/2022/12/20/towards-generative-vr</id><content type="html" xml:base="/featured/2022/12/20/towards-generative-vr.html"><![CDATA[<p>A new conference paper with our partners from the Technion Arc. Eytan Mann and Prof. Aaron Sprecher.</p>

<p>This paper envisions a pipeline for automating the generation of augmented reality tours of contested heritage sites while employing a critical approach toward the representation of history. Through the design of a generative pipeline, the paper identifies and discusses the potential and pitfalls associated with extracting spatial features from archival manuscripts and presenting them using an augmented reality application. The paper proposes a number of design approaches that assist in automating the transformation of manuscripts into interactive tours while taking into consideration historical, narrative, and technical challenges.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/366225666_Toward_a_Generative_Pipeline_for_an_AR_Tour_of_Contested_Heritage_Sites">Read the full paper</a></p>]]></content><author><name>jonathan-dortheimer</name></author><category term="featured" /><category term="VR" /><category term="AI" /><category term="digital herritage" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new conference paper with our partners from the Technion Arc. Eytan Mann and Prof. Aaron Sprecher.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/papers/vr.gif" /><media:content medium="image" url="/images/papers/vr.gif" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">New open-access research paper- Collective Intelligence in Design Crowdsourcing</title><link href="/2022/11/29/CI-paper.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New open-access research paper- Collective Intelligence in Design Crowdsourcing" /><published>2022-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-15T08:34:07+00:00</updated><id>/2022/11/29/CI-paper</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2022/11/29/CI-paper.html"><![CDATA[<p>This study investigates how collective intelligence emerges in crowdsourcing for architectural design. Previous studies have revealed that collective intelligence emerges from the collaboration and can outperform individual intelligence. As design is a highly collaborative practice, collective intelligence plays a vital role in the design process. In this study, we compare the structure of two architectural design crowdsourcing systems using several methods. The results of the analysis suggest that design crowdsourcing systems can give rise to the following three types of collective intelligence:</p>

<ul>
<li>Discussive, which emerges from a conversation between designers and clients</li>
    <li>Synthetic, which emerges from a parallel and sequential design development</li>
    <li>Evaluative, which is based on the wisdom of the crowd in evaluating and selecting designs</li>
</ul>
<p>The article concludes with recommendations for collaborative design method.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.mdpi.com/2227-7390/10/4/539">Read the full paper</a></p>]]></content><author><name>jonathan-dortheimer</name></author><category term="collective intelligence" /><category term="chatbots" /><category term="participatory design" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This study investigates how collective intelligence emerges in crowdsourcing for architectural design. Previous studies have revealed that collective intelligence emerges from the collaboration and can outperform individual intelligence. As design is a highly collaborative practice, collective intelligence plays a vital role in the design process. In this study, we compare the structure of two architectural design crowdsourcing systems using several methods. The results of the analysis suggest that design crowdsourcing systems can give rise to the following three types of collective intelligence:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New open-access research paper - Collective Intelligence in Design Crowdsourcing</title><link href="/2022/11/29/new-ci-paper.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New open-access research paper - Collective Intelligence in Design Crowdsourcing" /><published>2022-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-15T08:34:07+00:00</updated><id>/2022/11/29/new-ci-paper</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2022/11/29/new-ci-paper.html"><![CDATA[<p>We published a new open access research paper.</p>

<p>This study investigates how collective intelligence emerges in crowdsourcing for architectural design. Previous studies have revealed that collective intelligence emerges from the collaboration and can outperform individual intelligence. As design is a highly collaborative practice, collective intelligence plays a vital role in the design process. In this study, we compare the structure of two architectural design crowdsourcing systems using several methods. The results of the analysis suggest that design crowdsourcing systems can give rise to the following three types of collective intelligence:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Discussive, which emerges from a conversation between designers and clients

Synthetic, which emerges from a parallel and sequential design development

Evaluative, which is based on the wisdom of the crowd in evaluating and selecting designs
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The article concludes with recommendations for collaborative design method.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.mdpi.com/2227-7390/10/4/539">Read the full paper</a></p>]]></content><author><name>jonathan-dortheimer</name></author><category term="crowdsourcing" /><category term="collective intelligence" /><category term="AI" /><category term="participatory design" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We published a new open access research paper.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Conference presentation “Automating Community Design Conversations in Urban Design using Chatbots and Machine Learning</title><link href="/2022/11/28/urbanism-conference.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conference presentation “Automating Community Design Conversations in Urban Design using Chatbots and Machine Learning" /><published>2022-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-15T08:34:07+00:00</updated><id>/2022/11/28/urbanism-conference</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2022/11/28/urbanism-conference.html"><![CDATA[<p>The conference “The second conference of the Israel Urban Studies Community” will take place on the 27th of October at the Open University campus. I have worked on this project with Nikolas Martelaro, Gerhard Schubert, and Aaron Sprecher. Here is the abstract of my talk:</p>

<p>Urban design is an institutional process aimed at developing cities and improving communities. Since cities are complex systems that include many subsystems – urban design is a particularly challenging task. As a result, urban design is usually a top-down process characterized by a disconnect between designers and residents. Critics of postmodern urban planning argued that this approach led to inferior design in major urban projects.</p>

<p>To deal with this challenge in the last 60 years, participatory design methods have gained popularity, allowing residents to participate in urban planning through various tools, such as workshops, interviews, and meetings. Some argue that participatory design practices are essential to creating “just cities” and sustainable communities. However, there are many significant challenges related to politics, knowledge gaps, distrust in the system, and lack of democratic tradition, time, and resources.</p>

<p>This project offers an artificial intelligence tool to tackle some of these challenges by automating design conversations with thousands of residents in urban projects. From the participatory design perspective, the tool allows residents to influence and intervene in design decisions before and during the planning process through conversations. We developed a chatbot using a machine learning model that can discuss an architectural project with various stakeholders and automatically generate a design brief.</p>

<p>To test the efficiency and usefulness of the technology, we conducted an experiment in which the participants talked to the chatbot about establishing a new architecture school. The system then produced a list of design requirements from the conversations, and the participants rated their accuracy. Finally, participants completed a user experience survey.</p>

<p>The experiment results indicate both the promises and the challenges of this technology. The results showed that the chatbot could hold meaningful conversations with the project stakeholders, reflect the conversation’s essence through the design requirements list and have a positive user experience. However, on the other hand, there is difficulty in controlling the conversation, and there is a lack of trust in the capabilities of artificial intelligence.</p>]]></content><author><name>jonathan-dortheimer</name></author><category term="crowdsourcing" /><category term="chatbots" /><category term="AI" /><category term="participatory design" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The conference “The second conference of the Israel Urban Studies Community” will take place on the 27th of October at the Open University campus. I have worked on this project with Nikolas Martelaro, Gerhard Schubert, and Aaron Sprecher. Here is the abstract of my talk:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Novel Crowdsourcing-based Approach for Collaborative Architectural Design</title><link href="/2022/01/01/architasker.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Novel Crowdsourcing-based Approach for Collaborative Architectural Design" /><published>2022-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-15T08:34:07+00:00</updated><id>/2022/01/01/architasker</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2022/01/01/architasker.html"><![CDATA[<p>We published a new paper that provides an overview of “Architasker”, a large-scale crowdsourcing approach, platform, and method that enables a collaborative professional architectural design process in collaboration with a community of stakeholders.</p>

<p>The platform includes communicating complex architectural project requirements; solution space exploration using different micro-tasks like sketching, 2D and 3D CAD; design selection; and design review as an evolutionary process.</p>

<p>The architectural crowdsourcing model underlying the platform is contextualized in the state-of-the-art research on creative crowdsourcing methods and is supported by relevant evidence from empirical experiments. Experimental results validate the effectiveness of the method to generate architectural artifacts by harnessing the skills, talents, and experience of architects and the opinions and values of the stakeholders.</p>

<p><a href="http://papers.cumincad.org/data/works/att/ecaade2020_037.pdf">Read the full paper here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>jonathan-dortheimer</name></author><category term="crowdsourcing" /><category term="ecaade" /><category term="participatory design" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We published a new paper that provides an overview of “Architasker”, a large-scale crowdsourcing approach, platform, and method that enables a collaborative professional architectural design process in collaboration with a community of stakeholders.]]></summary></entry></feed>